Dan Musser

♠ Minneapolis, MN

<u>(651)</u> 808-0403

<u>musserdn@gmail.com</u>

in LinkedIn

Skills

- ◆ SAP ◆ Maximo ◆ Jira ◆ Confluence
- ♦ Workday ◆ Asset Management
- ♦ Warehouse Management Systems
- ◆ Inventory Management ◆ Smartsheet
- ◆ Insomnia ◆ Product Operations
- ♦ SQL ♦ Micro Services ♦ UI/UX
- ♦ Kibana ♦ Grafana ♦ Product Health
- ◆ Product Efficiency ◆ ServiceNow

Certifications

- Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO) - Scrum Alliance
- Certified Professional Agile Product Ownership - ICAgile

Education

Masters of Public Health Environmental Health Sciences

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities Received September 2013 GPA 3.9/4.0

Bachelor of Science Chemical Engineering

University of Minnesota - Duluth Received May 2007 GPA 3.2/4.0

Summary

Product Manager with 10+ years of experience in driving operational efficiency, investment optimization and product delivery. Empathetic leader with a focus on utilizing data in storytelling and prioritization. Possesses the curiosity to dig deep, understand broadly, and solve big problems collaboratively. Demonstrated ability to translate business goals and requirements into actional plans and technical solutions. Seeking to bring my passion, analysis skills, and leadership to a high-performing product organization.

Professional Experience

Target Corporation - Minneapolis, MN

Sr. Product Manager - Warehouse Management
April 2022 - Present

- Implemented product features to increase accuracy, safety and efficiency of inventory location management;
- Increased product availability and quality through weekly audits;
- ◆ Reduced the amount of non-productive space and inventory;
- ◆ Optimized the correction of inventory defects across enterprise;
- ◆ Enabled the evaluation of real time enterprise space, capacity and utilization metrics;
- ◆ Leveraged data analysis to drive product opportunities and key results;
- ◆ Managed the deprecation of multiple duplicative legacy systems to reduce product incidents, downtime, and meantime to restore.

Lead Business Partner - Assets Protection Technology June 2019 - April 2022

- ◆ Optimized asset replacement strategy for 160k camera system;
- ◆ Reduced downtime and outages for critical surveillance;
- Implemented guest counting and real time camera vision safety alerts;
- Collaborated on programs in reducing theft, shortage, and safety incidents;
- ◆ Managed the technical access control solution for Drive Up.

Senior Program Owner - Property Management August 2014 - June 2019

- Executed strategies to maximum asset lifecycles;
- ◆ Optimized a \$30M+ capital investment program:
- ◆ Implemented vendor performance and strategic sourcing events;
- Evaluated asset data and modeling to predict asset failures;
- ◆ Managed preventative maintenance programs to increase lifespan and decrease asset expenses.

Bay West LLC - Saint Paul, MN

Engineer / Health and Safety Specialist

November 2007 - August 2014

- ◆ Implemented and optimized soil and groundwater remediation systems;
- Managed health, safety and compliance programs;
- ◆ Performed data analysis, trending and modeling of sample collections;
- Managed the execution of client consulting projects.